Dr. Guglielmo Gemignani

Residence: Munich, Germany

Tel: +49 1525 7841084

Email: guglielmogemignani@gmail.com



in (7) 🤄

Brief Research Statement

A highly experienced professional in the field of robotics and AI with over 10 years of experience programming robots and over 5 years of experience managing teams of engineers. Holds a PhD in Robotics and Artificial Intelligence and has strong technical and interpersonal skills. Has contributed to the field with over 20 academic publications and 2 patents, and has participated in European projects.

Skills

Management: 5+ years. Trained in Agile Development, Nonviolent Communication, and Effective Leadership

Programming: 10+ years. Experience primarily with Python, C++, and Prolog in ROS

Languages: Italian (native), English (fluent), German (B2), French (A2)

Employment Experiences

MAGAZINO GMBH

Head of Robotic Integration (03/2022 - Present)

Disciplinary supervisor and technical lead of a team of 10+ developers in charge of robot architecture design, robot behaviors development and product QA. Additionally, responsible for a commercial Behavior Tree based framework, adopted by multiple multinational companies to develop behaviors for their autonomous robots.

Keywords: VDA5050, Integrator CLI, SW & HW QA, Gazebo, GitLab, Docker, Podman, Behavior Trees.

Team Lead Behaviors & Reasoning (01/2018 - 03/2022)

Disciplinary supervisor and technical lead of a team in charge of robot behaviors development, data analysis, and SW QA. The team contributed to the development of three products: TORU, SOTO, ACROS.AI. *Keywords: Behavior trees, Automated planning, SW QA, Gazebo, Buildbot, Data Analysis, Pandas, Jupyter, GCP.*

Senior Robotics Software Engineer (02/2017 - 01/2018)

Responsible for the behaviors, navigation and deployment of TORU.

The robot won several awards, such as Best ROS Based Product 2020, Best product LogiMAT 2018, etc. *Keywords: ROS, Behavior Trees, Django, Diagnostics, Prolog, Error modeling and Handling*.

Robotics Software Engineer (11/2015 - 02/2017)

Robot navigation and behavior developer.

Keywords: ROS, Move Base, Topological graph planner, NetworkX, Django, Behavior Trees.

Additional Experiences

Open and Closed Source Contributions

Author/maintainer/contributor of various open and closed source projects

Repositories: ros/diagnostics, UP4ROS2, pyswip, PetriNetPlans, ros/geometry2, behavior_trees, robot_state_reasoning, topological_graph_planner, etc.

Academic and Research Roles

European Project Reviewer

Project Names: SciRoc (EU-H2020 funded project)

SPC, PC and Reviewer for various international conferences

Conferences: IJCAI, ECAI, AI*IA, etc.

International Research Project Contributor

Project Names: AIPlan4EU (EU-H2020 funded project), RoboDevOps (Bavarian funded project)

RoboCup 2013 Standard Platform League

Team Leader and coordination and behaviors developer of the SPQR team

Achieved 1st place at Iran Open 2013 & 3rd place at German Open 2013

Education

CARNEGIE MELLON UNIVERSITY

PhD Visitor: CORAL Laboratory under the supervision of Prof. Manuela Veloso *Visiting Period*: 09/2014 - 03/2015

Sapienza - Università di Roma, Italy

PhD in Robotics and Artificial Intelligence (11/2012 - 02/2016)

 ${\it Title~of~the~Thesis}: \ Acquiring \ Knowledge \ Through \ Multi-Modal \ Human-Robot \ Interaction$

Advisor: Prof. Daniele Nardi

Laurea Magistrale in Electronic Physics (09/2010 - 10/2012)

Title of the Thesis: Study of the Readout System of a Microcapillary Position Detector Filled with Scintillating Liquid

Grade: 110/110 cum laude, excellence program

Università degli Studi di Pisa, Italy

Laurea Triennale in Physics (09/2007 - 07/2010)

Title of the Thesis: Numerical Solution of the Unidimensional Scrödinger Equation

Publications

JOURNALS, BOOK CHAPTERS, AND PATENTS

- Capabilities for error categorization, reporting and introspection of a technical apparatus. **G. Gemignani**, M. Grimm, M. Tenorth. European Patent and Trademark Office, filed on August 8th, 2021.
- Controlling an apparatus, e.g., a robot, with a behavior tree. **G. Gemignani**. European Patent and Trademark Office, filed on February 4th, 2021.
- *Dialogue with Robots to Support Symbiotic Autonomy*. A. Vanzo, D. Croce, E. Bastianelli, **G. Gemignani**, R. Basili, D. Nardi. Dialogues with Social Robots, pp. 331-342, 2017.
- Living with Robots: Interactive Environmental Knowledge Acquisition. G. Gemignani, R. Capobianco, E. Bastianelli, D. D. Bloisi, L. Iocchi, D. Nardi. Robotics and Autonomous Systems, RAS 2016.

CONFERENCES

- Planning for Automated Testing of Implicit Constraints in Behavior Trees. U. Köckemann, D. Calisi, **G. Gemignani**, J. Renoux, and A. Saffiotti. International Conference on Automated Planning and Scheduling, ICAPS 2023.
- Automatic Extraction of Structural Representations of Environments. R. Capobianco, **G. Gemignani**, D. D. Bloisi, D. Nardi, and L. Iocchi. Chapter in Intelligent Autonomous Systems 13, 2016.
- Multi-Robot Search for a Moving Target: Integrating World Modeling, Task Assignment and Context. F. Riccio, E. Borzi,G. Gemignani, and D. Nardi. International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems, IROS 2016.RoboCup Best Paper Award.
- *Multi-Robot Task Acquisition through Sparse Coordination*. S. Klee, **G. Gemignani**, M. Veloso, and D. Nardi. International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems, IROS 2015.
- Disambiguating Localization Symmetry through a Multi-Clustered Particle Filtering. F. Previtali, G. Gemignani, L. Iocchi and D. Nardi. International Conference on Multisensor Fusion and Information Integration 2015.
- *Graph-Based Task Libraries for Robots: Generalization and Autocompletion.* **G. Gemignani**, S. D. Klee, D. Nardi, and M. Veloso. AI*IA 2015.
- Approaching Qualitative Spatial Reasoning About Distances and Directions in Robotics. **G. Gemignani**, R. Capobianco, and D. Nardi. AI*IA 2015.
- Language-Based Sensing Descriptors for Robot Object Grounding. G. Gemignani, M. Veloso, and D. Nardi. RoboCup Symposium 2015. Best Paper Award.
- *Context-based Coordination for a Multi-Robot Soccer Team.* F. Riccio, E. Borzi, **G. Gemignani**, and D. Nardi. RoboCup Symposium 2015.
- On Task Recognition and Generalization in Long-Term Robot Teaching (Extended Abstract). G. Gemignani, S. Klee, M. Veloso, and D. Nardi. 14th International Conference on Autonomous Agents and Multiagent Systems, AAMAS 2015.
- Teaching Robots Parametrized Executable Plans Through Spoken Interaction. **G. Gemignani**, E. Bastinaelli, and D. Nardi. 14th International Conference on Autonomous Agents and Multiagent Systems, AAMAS 2015.

- Automatic Extraction of Structural Representations of Environments. R. Capobianco, G. Gemignani, D. Bloisi, D. Nardi, and L. Iocchi. 13th International Conference on Intelligent Autonomous Systems, IAS 2014.
- *On-line Semantic Mapping*. E. Bastianelli, D. Bloisi, R. Capobianco, F. Cossu, **G. Gemignani**, L. Iocchi, and D. Nardi. 16th International Conference on Advanced Robotics, ICAR 2013.

WORKSHOPS

- *Dialog with Robots to Support Symbiotic Autonomy*. D. Nardi, R. Basili, E. Bastianelli, D. Croce, **G. Gemignani**, A. Vanzo. In Proceedings of the 7th International Workshop on Spoken Dialog Systems, 2016.
- Contexts for Symbiotic Autonomy: Semantic Mapping, Task Teaching and Social Robotics. R. Capobianco, G. Gemignani, L. Iocchi, D. Nardi, F. Riccio, and A. Vanzo. In Proceedings of the AAAI'16 Workshop on Symbiotic Cognitive Systems, 2016.
- *Interactive Semantic Mapping: Experimental Evaluation.* **G. Gemignani**, D. Nardi, D. D. Bloisi, R. Capobianco, and L. Iocchi. Springer Tracts in Advanced Robotics, Experimental Robotics, 2016.
- Multi Robot Perception and Action: World Modeling and Task Allocation. F. Riccio, M. T. Lazáro, G. Gemignani, and D. Nardi. RSS 2015 Workshop Principle of multi-robot systems.
- *Task Recognition and Generalization in Long-Term Robot Teaching*. **G. Gemignani**, S. Klee, M. Veloso, and D. Nardi. Autonomous Robots and Multirobot Systems, ARMS 2015.
- *Symbiotic Semantic Mapping*. **G. Gemignani**, D. Nardi, D. D. Bloisi, R. Capobianco, and L. Iocchi. International Symposium on Experimental Robotics, ISER 2014.
- *Knowledge-Based Reasoning on Semantic Maps.* R. Capobianco, **G. Gemignani**, D. Nardi, D. Bloisi, and L. Iocchi. Knowledge Representation and Reasoning in Robotics Symposium at AAAI Spring Symposium, 2014.
- Knowledge Representation for Robots through Human-Robot Interaction. E. Bastianelli, D. Bloisi, R. Capobianco,
 G. Gemignani, L. Iocchi, and D. Nardi. Knowledge Representation and Reasoning in Robotics Workshop at 29th International Conference on Logic Programming, 2013.